{
    "id": "5167dd1e7cf7411c99f2720df4531f54",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Are you not ashamed ……………………?",
            "description": "Ashamed is used with of the reflexive pronoun is used when the subject and the object refer to the same person.",
            "answers": [
                "of yourself",
                "with yourself",
                "of you"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "When we lived in Bangalore, we …………………….. go out every evening.",
            "description": "Both would and used to can be used to talk about past habits.",
            "answers": [
                "used to",
                "would use to",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The room was ............................. dark that I couldn’t see anything.",
            "description": "Note the pattern so...that",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "very",
                "too"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………….. had I finished reading one book, when I started another.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "As soon as",
                "Hardly",
                "Scarcely"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "………………… he was suffering from fever, he didn’t go out.",
            "description": "As is used to give the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Though",
                "If"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the house …………………… he lives.",
            "description": "Where means in which.",
            "answers": [
                "there",
                "where",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me …………………….. I had finished.",
            "description": "Both if and whether can be used to introduce an indirect question. ",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Iron as well as coal ……………………… found in India.",
            "description": "When we connect two singular nouns with as well as, the verb should be singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is",
                "has"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He has been learning English ………………………. 5 years.",
            "description": "We use for with duration.",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "since",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Even if you invited him, he ……………………….. come.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not",
                "would not",
                "shall not"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. the cops, the thieves ran away.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Seeing",
                "Seen",
                "Saw"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were the Prime Minister, I ………………........... capital punishment.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will abolish",
                "would abolish",
                "would have abolished"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}